[
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "In which month of the year do we see the Perseid meteor shower?",
    "Answer": "August"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the maximom number of solar eclipses which we can see in a year?",
    "Answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "It takes how many minutes for light from the Sun to reach Earth?",
    "Answer": "8 minutes"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "The Vredefort crater, left over from a meteorite impact, is in which country?",
    "Answer": "South Africa"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "Viking Lander, the first spacecraft to land on Mars, touched down in which year?",
    "Answer": "1976"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "Total solar eclipses happen on average every how many months?",
    "Answer": "18 months"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for one celestial body passing in front of another?",
    "Answer": "Transit"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for areas which appear dark on the surface of the sun?",
    "Answer": "Sunspots"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for a planet outside the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Exoplanet"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "General Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "Oberon, Titania, and Miranda are moons of which planet?",
    "Answer": "Uranus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet do astronomers sometimes call a failed star?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for a small body orbiting the sun, made of rock or metal?",
    "Answer": "Asteroid"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "What kind of hole is created when a star collapses?",
    "Answer": "Black"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "NASA's Cassini space probe orbited which planet?",
    "Answer": "Saturn"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Shooting star is another name for which object?",
    "Answer": "Meteor"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet is home to Ganymede, the biggest moon in the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Triton is the largest moon of which planet?",
    "Answer": "Neptune"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet has moons called Phobos and Deimos?",
    "Answer": "Mars"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet has a moon called Triton?",
    "Answer": "Neptune"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Triton is the moon of which planet?",
    "Answer": "Neptune"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet is known as 'the ringed planet'?",
    "Answer": "Saturn"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "How many planets in our solar system are classed as gas giants?",
    "Answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Venus has how many moons?",
    "Answer": "0"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "How many moons does Mars have?",
    "Answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "How many terrestrial planets do we have in our solar system?",
    "Answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet in the solar system has more than 75 moons?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Uranus takes how many Earth days to orbit the sun?",
    "Answer": "84"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the coldest planet in the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Uranus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "The hottest planet in the solar system has a surface temperature of how many centigrade?",
    "Answer": "450\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "A year on Mercury is equivalent to how many days on Earth?",
    "Answer": "88"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the second smallest planet in the solar system after Mercury?",
    "Answer": "Mars"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Planets Trivia",
    "Question": "Which is the fastest spinning planet in the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the term for any man-made object orbiting Earth?",
    "Answer": "Space Junk"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "Which country launched the Marsnik 1 space probe in 1960?",
    "Answer": "USSR"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "The Akatsuki mission to explore weather on Venus was launched by which country?",
    "Answer": "Japan"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the NASA mission to explore Pluto and the Kuiper Belt?",
    "Answer": "New Horizons"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "Which country launched the Hubble Space Telescope?",
    "Answer": "United States"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "The Hubble Space Telescope orbits how many miles above Earth?",
    "Answer": "350 miles"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "Cassini-Huygens was a space mission launched by NASA, the European Space Agency, and which country?",
    "Answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "In which year was the Hubble Space Telescope launched?",
    "Answer": "1990"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Space Exploration & Discovery Trivia",
    "Question": "NASA's Mars Curiosity Rover was launched in which year?",
    "Answer": "2011"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "92.1% of the sun is made up of which gas?",
    "Answer": "Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "The sun accounts for what percentage of the mass of the solar system?",
    "Answer": "99.80%"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "The sun is composed of hydrogen and which other gas?",
    "Answer": "Helium"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "How many times bigger than Earth is the Sun?",
    "Answer": "110"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the approximate diameter of the Sun in kilometers?",
    "Answer": "1.4 million kilometers"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the primary source of energy for the Sun?",
    "Answer": "Nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the outermost layer of the Sun's atmosphere called?",
    "Answer": "Corona"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the average temperature of the Sun's surface in degrees Celsius?",
    "Answer": "Around 5,500 degrees Celsius"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "How long does it take for the Sun's light to reach the Earth in minutes?",
    "Answer": "About 8 minutes"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the process that powers the Sun, where hydrogen atoms fuse to form helium?",
    "Answer": "Nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the Sun's visible surface?",
    "Answer": "Photosphere"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the Sun's approximate mass compared to the Earth's mass?",
    "Answer": "About 333,000 times the mass of the Earth"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "How many Earths could fit inside the Sun?",
    "Answer": "Approximately 1.3 million Earths"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the Sun predominantly composed of?",
    "Answer": "Hydrogen and helium"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the term for a sudden, bright eruption on the Sun's surface?",
    "Answer": "Solar flare"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the Sun's approximate age in billions of years?",
    "Answer": "Around 4.6 billion years"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the Sun's magnetic field that extends far into space?",
    "Answer": "Heliosphere"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the Sun's approximate rotation period at its equator?",
    "Answer": "About 25 days"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Sun Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for the phenomenon of the Sun appearing completely covered by the Moon during an eclipse?",
    "Answer": "Total solar eclipse"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "In which century was the first asteroid discovered?",
    "Answer": "19th"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "In which year was Uranus discovered?",
    "Answer": "1781"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "What celestial body crashing into Earth is thought to have ended the dinosaurs?",
    "Answer": "Asteroid"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "The solar system planets are classed as Gas Giants and which other group?",
    "Answer": "Terrestrial"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "What comes after 'Kuiper' for an area of space beyond Pluto?",
    "Answer": "Belt"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for a cloud of dust and gas in interstellar space?",
    "Answer": "Nebula"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "How many general types of galaxies are there?",
    "Answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "How many spiral arms does our galaxy have?",
    "Answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name for snowballs of frozen gases, rocks, and dust?",
    "Answer": "Comet"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet is referred to as the 'morning star'?",
    "Answer": "Venus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Astronomy Trivia",
    "Question": "In which year was Pluto reclassified as a dwarf planet?",
    "Answer": "2006"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Solar System Features Trivia",
    "Question": "What comes after 'Kuiper' in the name of a solar system feature near Neptune?",
    "Answer": "Belt"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Solar System Features Trivia",
    "Question": "What comes after 'Swift' in the name of a comet which is visible every 133 years?",
    "Answer": "Tuttle"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Solar System Features Trivia",
    "Question": "What comes after 'Oort' in the name of a very distant region of the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Cloud"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Solar System Features Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the theoretical shell of icy objects beyond the Kuiper Belt?",
    "Answer": "Oort Cloud"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Comets & Asteroids Trivia",
    "Question": "Halley's comet will next pass Earth in which year?",
    "Answer": "2061"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Comets & Asteroids Trivia",
    "Question": "In which decade did Halley's comet last pass Earth?",
    "Answer": "1980s"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Comets & Asteroids Trivia",
    "Question": "The Kuiper Belt lies beyond the orbit of which planet?",
    "Answer": "Neptune"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Comets & Asteroids Trivia",
    "Question": "The asteroid belt lies between Mars and which planet?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet in the solar system has 67 confirmed and named moons?",
    "Answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "William Herschel discovered Uranus in which century?",
    "Answer": "18th"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which was the first planet to be discovered by scientists?",
    "Answer": "Uranus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Jupiter's Great Red Spot was first identified in which year?",
    "Answer": "1665"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon in our solar system is the largest?",
    "Answer": "Ganymede"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the moon that orbits the planet Mars?",
    "Answer": "Phobos and Deimos"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Jupiter is known for its intense volcanic activity?",
    "Answer": "Io"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Saturn is the only known moon with a substantial atmosphere?",
    "Answer": "Titan"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the largest moon of Neptune?",
    "Answer": "Triton"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Uranus is known for its unique sideways rotation?",
    "Answer": "Miranda"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Saturn has a prominent ridge running along its equator?",
    "Answer": "Iapetus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Jupiter is famous for its colorful and vibrant surface?",
    "Answer": "Europa"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Pluto?",
    "Answer": "Charon"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Saturn is known for its icy plumes erupting from its south pole?",
    "Answer": "Enceladus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Neptune is the only known moon to have a retrograde orbit?",
    "Answer": "Triton"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Saturn?",
    "Answer": "Titan"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Uranus has a distinct feature called \"The Great Dark Spot\"?",
    "Answer": "Umbriel"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Venus?",
    "Answer": "None (Venus does not have any moons)"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Moons Trivia",
    "Question": "Which moon of Jupiter was discovered by Galileo Galilei in 1610?",
    "Answer": "The Galilean moons (Io, Europa, Ganymede, Callisto)"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Miscellaneous Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "Which planet is named after the Roman goddess of love and beauty?",
    "Answer": "Venus"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Miscellaneous Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "The moon has what proportion of the gravity on Earth?",
    "Answer": "Sixth"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Miscellaneous Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "What is the name of the theoretical boundary at the edge of the solar system?",
    "Answer": "Heliopause"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Miscellaneous Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "How many days does it take the moon to orbit the Earth?",
    "Answer": "27.3"
  },
  {
    "Topic": "Miscellaneous Solar System Trivia",
    "Question": "Astronomer Johann Bode, who discovered Uranus, came from which country?",
    "Answer": "Germany"
  }
]